Register of the Elizabeth Churchill Brown Papers 1943-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
Elizabeth Churchill Brown papers
1943-1984
84010
Hoover Institution Archives
41 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes (17 linear feet)
Memoirs, other writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to American politics, especially during the 1950s; Senator Joseph McCarthy; and American communism. Includes some papers, including memoirs, of Constantine Brown, journalist and husband of E. C. Brown. Also includes some letters and writings of Earl Browder.
Brown, Elizabeth Churchill
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical Note
Elizabeth Brown and her husband, Constantine Brown, were active journalists in Washington, D.C. and abroad for many years. As a result, they established contacts with key political and diplomatic figures both nationally and internationally. After obtaining a Ph.D. in political science from the University of Berlin (c. 1912), Constantine Brown was in Cambridge, England doing post-graduate work when World War I began. He covered the war on the Russian front for the London Times, was in Russia when the Revolution began, and was one of the first American newspapermen to interview Lenin. He subsequently became Bureau Chief for the Chicago Daily News in Turkey, Paris and London, and moved to the Washington Evening Star as Foreign Affairs Editor in 1932. In 1942, he began writing a column syndicated by the Bell-McClure organization. His memoirs, entitled The Coming of the Whirlwind, were published in 1964. Disturbed by the defeat of Richard Nixon in 1960 and the liberal emphasis of the Kennedy administration, the Browns decided to move to Europe, living in Rome from 1961 to early 1965. After returning to Washington, Constantine Brown died on Feb. 24, 1966.
Elizabeth Brown, who was born in 1908, worked as a society reporter, first for the New York Evening Journal, then for Town and Country magazine and the Washington Post. She married Constantine Brown in 1949. Impressed by his analyses, she became interested in issues of American foreign and domestic policy, and began writing more substantive materials. Living in Washington during the early 1950s, the Browns were friendly with Joseph R. and Jean McCarthy, as well as a number of other prominent conservatives. In 1956 she published a book, entitled The Enemy at His Back, about Communist influence on post-World War II American foreign policy. She also wrote another book, more specifically about the McCarthy era. This was tentatively entitled Joe McCarthy and Other Anti-Communists: A Memoir of Conservative Politics in the Washington of the Early Nineteen Fifties, but was never published. Mrs. Brown continued to write after Mr. Brown's death, including a long series for William Loeb and the Manchester Union Leader.
McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Internal security--United States.; Journalists.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; United States--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1973. (Box 1)
  General note
  Biographical sketches, business cards, correspondence, clippings, lecture notices, memoranda, miscellany, printed article, printed hearing transcript, travel guides, arranged by subject.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1978. (Box 1-4)
  Significant correspondence of Constantine and Elizabeth Brown, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes a few letters neither to nor from the Browns.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1951-1977. (Box 4-12)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches and writings with related correspondence, notes, and other material, arranged by form, and thereunder chronologically.
- CONSTANTINE BROWN, 1945-1965. (Box 13-15)
  Published and unpublished writings and related correspondence of Constantine Brown; and published and unpublished writings and correspondence of others, relating to Constantine Brown, arranged by form.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1837-1984. (Box 15-41)
  Published and unpublished speeches and writings of others, correspondence, reports, and other material arranged alphabetically by topic. Broadly covers issues of American foreign and domestic policy, particularly Communism and anti-Communism during the McCarthy period.
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1950-1968 (Envelope A, mB)
  Scope and Contents note
  18 prints, 2 negatives, 68 postcards/ 2 envelopes
- DECLASSIFIED RECORDS, 1958, undated (Box 41)
  Formerly security-classified government records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1973
  - General, 1946-1973 (Box 1)
    - Constantine Brown, 1946-1973 (Folder 1)
      - Biographical sketches, n.d.
      - Career as a journalist, 1946-1973
        - General. Commendations, correspondence, printed article, an entry pass for an interview with Francisco Franco, and miscellany, 1946-1973
        - Clippings, 1957-1962
      - Transcript of testimony before House Un-American Activities Committee, 1957 Oct. 21
    - Elizabeth Churchill Brown. Certificates, clippings and lecture notices, 1958-1960 (Folder 2-3)
  - Miscellany. Clippings, correspondence, invitations, memoranda, and sketch of Constantine Brown, 1952-1965 (Folder 4)
  - World travels. Business cards, clippings, correspondence, guest lists, flyers, invitations, and pamphlets, 1946-1958 (Folder 5-6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1978
  - General, 1950-1967 (Box 1)
    - General, 1956-1967
      - General. Miscellaneous alphabetical, 1956-1967 (Folder 7)
      - Unidentified (Folder 8)
        - Dated, 1960-1965
        - Undated
    - Personal. Correspondence between Elizabeth and Constantine Brown, 1950-1964 (Folder 9)
  - Areilza, Jose de (Count of Montrico), 1960-1965 (Folder 10)
  - Barrett, Frank A. (Senator), 1957-1958 (Folder 11)
  - Bible, Alan (Senator), 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Bridges, Styles (Senator), 1959 (Folder 13)
  - Browder, Earl and Raissa, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Communism/ Internal security/Individuals/Browder, Earl and Raissa, 1954-1965. (Folder 14)
  - Byrd, Robert C. (Senator), 1959 (Folder 15)
  - Cartwright, John K. (Monsignor), 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Chiang, Kai-shek and Madame Chiang (Mayling Soong), 1956-1975 (Folder 17)
  - Christenberry, C.W. (General), 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Clarke, Carter (General)
    - 1950-1951 May (Folder 19)
    - 1951 June-1958 (Folder 20)
  - Corso, P.J., 1963 (Folder 21)
  - Cunningham, James (Father), 1963-1965 (Folder 22)
  - Derwinski, Ed, 1963 (Folder 23)
  - Dixon, Jeane, 1964-1967 (Folder 24)
  - Dodd, Thomas (Senator), 1961-1963 (Folder 25)
  - Dooman, Eugene, 1958 (Folder 26)
  - Eastland, James (Senator), 1959-1962 (Folder 27)
  - Fleeson, Doris, 1954 (Folder 28)
  - Fluegel, Edna R. (includes other family members), 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ford, Gerald R., 1963 (Folder 2)
  - Gannon, Frank and Clover, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Goldwater, Barry (Senator), 1957-1966 (Folder 4)
  - Hanighen, Frank, 1959-1963 (Folder 5)
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke B. (Senator), 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Hillenkoetter, R.H. (Admiral), 1951 (Folder 7)
  - Hillman, Alex L., 1961 (Folder 8)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1959-1970 (Folder 10)
  - Howard, Roy W., 1950-1959 (Folder 11)
  - Jackson, Henry M. (Senator), 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Johansen, August E., 1962 (Folder 13)
  - Kirk, Russell, 1963-1964 (Folder 14)
  - Klein, Herbert G., 1971 (Folder 15)
  - Knebel, Fletcher, 1960 (Folder 16)
  - Knight, Frances (Mrs. Wayne Parrish), 1955-1975 (Folder 17)
  - Knowland, William F. (Senator), 1959-1963 (Folder 18)
  - Koch, Fred C., 1961-1962 (Folder 19)
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1954-1962 (Folder 20)
  - Lalley, Joseph M., 1963 (Folder 21)
  - Leetch, Madalen, 1962 (Folder 22)
  - Lequerica, Jose Felix de, 1960 (Folder 23)
  - Loeb, William, 1958-1975 (Folder 24)
  - Lyons, Florence Fowler, 1960-1962 (Folder 25)
  - Mansfield, Mike (Senator), 1957 (Folder 26)
  - McGrath, W.L., 1955 (Folder 27)
  - McIntire, Carl (Reverend), 1964 (Folder 28)
  - Mundt, Karl (Senator), 1954-1964 (Folder 29)
  - Munson, Lyle, 1960-1972 (Folder 30)
  - Nichols, Louis B., 1959-1964 (Folder 31)
  - O'Conor, Herbert R., 1956 (Folder 32)
  - Pell, Robert, 1962-1965 (Folder 33)
  - Powell, Lewis, 1962 (Folder 34)
  - Radford, Arthur W. (Admiral), 1953 (Folder 35)
  - Rayburn, Sam, 1960 (Folder 36)
  - Regnery, Henry, 1954-1963 (Folder 37)
  - Rhee, Syngman and Francesca (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with the Browns
      - 1956-1957 (Folder 1)
      - 1958 (Folder 2)
      - 1959
        - Jan.-April (Folder 3)
        - May-July (Folder 4)
        - Sept.-Dec. (Folder 5)
      - 1960
        - Jan.-July (Folder 6)
        - Aug.-Dec. (Folder 7)
      - 1961-1962 (Folder 8)
      - 1963-1966 (Folder 9)
    - Official correspondence (copies obtained by Browns) (Folder 10)
      - General, 1957
      - Dulles, John Foster, 1957
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1957-1958
      - Kim, Chung Yul (Korean Minister of Defense), 1957
  - Rooney, John J., 1958 (Folder 11)
  - Sanchez Bella, Alfred de, 1965 (Folder 12)
  - Schaefer, J. Earl, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Smith, Truman, c. 1960 (Folder 14)
  - Sourwine, Jay, n.d. (Folder 15)
  - Lo Specchio, 1965-1967 (Folder 16)
  - Stahlman, James G., 1963 (Folder 17)
  - Starr, Charlotte, 1953-c. 1969 (Folder 18)
  - Stassen, Harold E., 1951 (Folder 19)
  - Thorin, Duane, 1960-1964 (Folder 20)
  - Thurmond, Strom (Senator), 1961-1964 (Folder 21)
  - Tower, John G. (Senator), 1962-1964 (Folder 22)
  - Trudeau, Arthur G. (General), c. 1954-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Utt, James B., 1962 (Folder 2)
  - The Wanderer (Walter and Joseph Matt, Editors), 1961-1964 (Folder 3)
  - War Information, Office of (Elmer Davis, Director), 1943 (Folder 4)
  - Wedemeyer, A.C. (General), 1964-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Welch, Joseph N., 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Welch, Robert (John Birch Society), 1956-1959 (Folder 7)
  - Wyman, Louis C., 1963 (Folder 8)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1951-1977
  - General, 1958-1977 (Box 4)
    - General. Notes, n.d. (Folder 9)
      - Holograph
      - Typescript
    - Scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, 1958-1966
    - Poems. Correspondence, printed articles, typescripts, c. 1960-1963, n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Political activism, c. 1959-1977
      - The State of the Nation. Project includes typescript drafts with notes, outlines, reports, c. 1959 (Folder 11)
      - To Conservative Activists. Drafts of letter/statement, notes, correspondence with Elbridge Durbrow (includes a typescript copy of Elbridge Durbrow, A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom), Frances Knight and others, 1977 (Folder 12)
  - Articles and speeches, Includes letters to editors, 1951-1977.
    - Fragments. Notes, typescript drafts (Folder 13)
    - Undated
      - Non-printed. Typescript drafts (Folder 14-16)
      - Printed. Clippings and printed articles (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Typescript draft, 1951. (Folder 2)
    - Typescript drafts, 1952. (Folder 3)
    - Typescript drafts, 1954. (Folder 4)
    - Typescript drafts, 1957. (Folder 5)
    - 1958
      - General. Typescripts, printed articles and clippings (photocopies and originals) (Folder 6-7)
      - Series for Colorado Springs Gazette Telegraph. Typescripts and clippings (Folder 8)
    - Clippings, printed articles, speech transcripts and typescripts, 1959. (Folder 9-10)
    - 1960
      - General. Typescript and clippings (Folder 11)
      - Series for Colorado Springs Gazette Telegraph. Clippings (Folder 12)
    - Letter to the editor (clippings), typescript drafts, 1961. (Folder 13-14)
    - 1962
      - General. Clippings and typescripts (Folder 15)
      - Analysis of the Statement of the Moscow Conference of the Representatives of Communist and Workers Parties, Dec. 6, 1960. Correspondence, printed article and typescript drafts (Folder 16-17)
    - Clippings, correspondence, typescript drafts. Some material in Italian, 1963. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1964
      - General. Clippings and typescripts (Folder 2)
      - Series for The Wanderer, 1964 Feb-Dec (Folder 3)
      - Series ascribed to Constantine Brown, but possibly written by Elizabeth C. Brown. Typescripts (Folder 4)
    - Clippings. Includes Manchester Union Leader, 1965. (Folder 5)
    - Typescript drafts and clippings, 1966.
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Series for The Manchester Union Leader (Folder 7-8)
    - Clippings and typescripts, 1967. (Folder 9)
    - 1968
      - General. Clippings and typescripts (Folder 10)
      - Interview with Richard Nixon for Lo Specchio, Includes typescript drafts, printed article (in Italian) and correspondence with Herbert Klein, Robert Murphy, Lou Nichols and Richard Nixon, 1968-1969. (Folder 11)
    - Typescript, 1969. (Folder 12)
    - Typescript drafts and clippings (some in Italian), 1970. (Folder 13)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1971. (Folder 14)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1972. (Folder 15)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1973. (Folder 16)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1974. (Folder 17)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Typescripts and clippings, 1976. (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence (letter to the editor), 1977. (Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts, 1955-1972
    - The Enemy at His Back, 1956
      - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Folder 4)
        - General. Requesting permission to quote other authors, 1956
        - Jaskievicz, W.C. (Fordham University), 1956
        - National Review (William F. Buckley Jr., Frank S. Meyer), 1956-1957
        - National War College (Admiral Thomas H. Robbins, Admiral E.T. Woolridge)
        - Naval War College (Admiral Thomas Robinson), 1957
        - Navy League Magazine, 1957
        - Newsweek (Raymond Moley), 1956-1957)
        - New York Herald Tribune (Ogden R. Reid), 1956
        - New York Times (Hanson W. Baldwin), 1956
        - Pegler, Westbrook (King Features Syndicate), 1957
        - Saturday Evening Post (Frederic Nelson), 1956
        - Reid, Mary Louise, 1956
        - The Retired Officer (Admiral W.G. Lalor), 1956
        - United States Naval Institute (Robert N. Adrian), 1957
        - Widener, Alice, 1956
        - Williams, Alford J., Jr., 1957
      - Drafts
        - Fragments (Folder 5)
        - Final draft
        - Notes (Folder 6-7)
      - Promotional material, 1955-1956
        - General. Typescripts and clippings (Folder 8)
        - Scrapbook. Clippings and reviews
      - Reviews and citations, 1956-1958 (Folder 9)
    - Joe McCarthy and Other Anti-Communists, c. 1967-1972 (Box 8)
      - General
        - Correspondence with Warren E. Magee, 1967 (Folder 1)
        - Fragments. Miscellaneous draft chapters (including 23 and 24) and deleted episodes. (Folder 2-8)
        - Notes (Folder 9)
      - Drafts
        - Number 1: Chapters 2-3 (Folder 10-11)
        - Number 1: Chapters 4-22 (Box 9, Folder 1-19)
        - Number 2: Prologue-Chapter 19. Includes annotations by Frank Hanighen (?) (Box 10, Folder 1-20)
        - Number 2: Chapters 20-22 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
        - Number 3: Rewritten by Lee Foster
          - General. Correspondence, Foster, Lee, 1972. (Folder 4)
          - Chapters 1-12 (Folder 5-16)
          - Remnants from original E.C.B. typescript
            - Chapters 1-2 (Folder 17)
            - Chapters 3-12 (Box 12, Folder 1-10)
        - Number 4: Final draft by Lee Foster (Folder 11-22)
- CONSTANTINE BROWN, 1945-1965
  - General. Clippings, correspondence, notes, 1955-1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1953-1954
  - Newspaper columns. Typescript drafts and clippings, 1945-1965
    - Fragments (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, clipping, typescripts (Folder 3)
    - Clippings and typescripts, 1945. (Folder 4)
    - Clippings and typescripts, 1950. (Folder 5)
    - Clipping, 1951. (Folder 6)
    - Clipping, 1952. (Folder 7)
    - Clippings, typescripts, correspondence and mimeographed memorandum, 1953. (Folder 8)
    - Clippings and mimeographed press releases, 1954. (Folder 9)
    - Typescript excerpts from C. Brown columns, 1955-1956. (Folder 10)
    - Clipping, 1957. (Folder 11)
    - Clippings, correspondence, typescripts, 1958. (Folder 12)
    - Typescripts and reprints. Includes typed copy of a letter from J. Edgar Hoover, 1959. (Folder 13)
    - Printed articles, reprints, and typescripts, 1962. (Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1964. (Folder 15)
    - Clippings and typescript, 1965. (Folder 16)
  - The Coming of the Whirlwind, 1964
    - General
      - Fragments (Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous sections (Folder 18)
    - Drafts
      - Number 1: Chapters 1-9 (Folder 19-27)
      - Number 2: Chapters 1-34 (Box 14, Folder 1-34)
      - Number 3: Table of Contents-Chapter 8 (Folder 35-44)
      - Number 3: Chapters 9-35 (Box 15, Folder 1-26)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1837-1984
  - Acheson, Dean. Mimeographed copy of statement before Senate Foreign Relations and Armed Services Committees, typescript transcripts and notes on testimony before House Foreign Affairs Committee, Includes speech transcript of Europe: Kaleidoscope or Clouded Crystal, 1946-1963. 1963 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Africa (Folder 28)
    - General. Newsletters, notes, pamphlets, statement by the African Students Union in the U.S.S.R.
    - Correspondence. Bureau of African Affairs, (Ghana), 1960
  - Agnew, Spiro T. Clipping, form letter, speech transcripts, c. 1970 (Folder 29)
  - Algeria. Printed and non-printed commentaries by Hilaire du Berrier, 1958-1960 (Folder 30)
  - Antarctica. Congressional resolution, press release (statement by President Eisenhower), reprint, 1954-1958 (Folder 31)
  - Asia. Clipping, newsletter, notes, press releases, reports, and mimeographed transcripts of speeches by Thomas J. Dodd, Jack Miller, James E. Murray and Walter S. Robertson, 1947-1973 (Folder 32)
  - Austria (South Tyrol). Correspondence, pamphlet and typescript report relating to autonomy for the South Tyrol, 1959-1966 (Folder 33)
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl. Newsletter, photocopy of anonymous confidential report, printed reports, 1960-1961 (Folder 34)
  - Canada. Newsletter relating to Pierre Trudeau, 1968 (Folder 35)
  - Carter, James E. Flyer, form letter, newsletters, notes, 1976-1978 (Folder 36)
  - Chile. Form letter, newsletters, pamphlets, press release, and a printed copy of Jeffrey B. Gayner and Lawrence D. Pratt, Allende and the Failure of Chilean Marxism, 1970-1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - China
    - People's Republic of China
      - General (Folder 2)
        - General. Flyers, map, notes, pamphlets, c. 1964-1980
        - Correspondence with Guy M. Gillette, V.S. Hsiang, Alfred Kohlberg, Madelen Leetch, Lucian B. Moody, Stephen M. Weld and others, 1950-1973
      - Foreign relations
        - General (Folder 3)
          - General. Newsletter, notes, memoranda, pamphlets, reports, resolutions, 1953-1970
          - U.N. admission question. Declarations, pamphlets, reprints, reports, 1965-1966
        - United States
          - Civil war period. Mimeographed copies of memoranda by foreign service officers in China (including John P. Davies and John Service), pamphlets, reports, transcripts of testimony before the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, wire reports, 1943-1971 (Folder 4)
          - Post-1949 period (Folder 5-6)
            - General. Clippings, flyers, newsletters, notes, pamphlets, reprints, transcripts (speeches and hearings) and typescript copy of P.C. Beezley, Toward Legitimate Protest, 1952-1971
            - Correspondence with Alfred Kohlberg, Committee of One Million, 1958
      - Internal affairs, Printed reports. Includes mimeographed notes on Congress of the Chinese Communist Party, Yenan, 1945-1971. 1945 (Folder 7)
    - Republic of China (Taiwan). Clippings, notes, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, speech transcripts, reprints, printed copy (pamphlet) of George S. Montgomery, Jr., A Second Term? Nationalist China and our 1956 Elections, printed speech transcript of James C.H. Shen, Sino-American Relations in Perspective, and mimeographed copy of A.C. Wedemeyer, Chiang Kai-Shek, Defender of Freedom, (memorial tribute, 1975), SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE/Chiang, Kai-Shek, 1950-1983. (Folder 8)
  - Communism
    - General
      - General. Clippings, newsletters, pamphlets, and anonymous typescript report on a meeting of the Religious Freedom Committee, 1950-1975 (Folder 9-10)
      - Correspondence with Time & Life, U.S. News and World Report, Alice Widener, 1952-1972 (Folder 11)
      - Notes (Folder 12)
    - Anti-communism
      - General. Campaign material, diagrams, newsletters, reference list, resolutions, speech transcript, correspondence with Life magazine and others (Folder 13)
        - Non-printed material, 1952-1960 (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Printed material
          - Newsletters
            - General, 1953-1959
            - Pink Sheet on the Left
              - #95-#111, (1/6/75-8/18/75) (Folder 2)
              - #112-#131, (9/1/75-5/4/76) (Folder 3)
          - Pamphlets (Folder 4)
      - Freedom Academy. Clippings, form letters, printed speech transcript (Thomas J. Dodd), correspondence with Francis J. McNamara, and others, 1959-1965 (Folder 5)
      - Matthews, J.B. Miscellany and correspondence, 1953-1958 (Folder 6)
      - McCarthy, Joseph. Clippings, correspondence, hearing transcripts, miscellany, newsletters, notes, pamphlets, speech transcripts, statements, resolutions, 1951-1983
        - Correspondence with John Butler, Ed C. Johnson, Joseph McCarthy, Gordon A. Sabine and others, 1951-1954 (Folder 7)
        - Miscellany and notes, c. 1951-1957 (Folder 8)
        - Non-printed material, general, 1952-1953 (Folder 9)
        - Printed material, general, 1951-1983
        - Speeches and writings, 1951-1955 (Folder 10)
    - Art. Newsletter, notes, an anonymous pamphlet, Minutes of a Communist Cell on Art, and correspondence with Hubert B. Scudder, 1952-1960 (Folder 11)
    - Communist Party - General (for individuals, SEE: Internal security/Individuals). Form letters, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, questionnaire, statements, reports, 1952-1971 (Folder 12)
      - Non-printed material. Mimeographed speech transcript of J. Edgar Hoover, The Communist Party U.S.A. and Its Present Status, and FBI (?) reports, 1954-1971
      - Printed material. Printed statements by J. Edgar Hoover, printed copy of Draft Resolutions for the 16th National Convention of the Communist Party U.S.A., 1952-1967
    - Education. Correspondence, flyers, miscellany, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, questionnaires, resolutions, teaching materials
      - General. Bibliography, clippings, correspondence, resolution and speech transcript relating to Arthur Prudden Coleman, 1948-1959 (Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1952-1961 (Folder 14)
      - Non-printed materials. Includes mimeographed copy (and notes) of H.A. Overstreet, A Reading Guide and Outline, 1952-1975 (Folder 15-16)
      - Printed material, 1941-1978 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Entertainment. Clippings, memoranda, miscellany, newsletters, pamphlets, press releases, resports, hearing transcripts, 1950-1980
      - General
        - Correspondence with Robert Dole, Warner Bros., and others, 1950-1970 (Folder 3)
        - Non-printed materials, 1951-c. 1959
        - Printed materials
          - General
          - Newsletters, 1957-1980
          - Pamphlets, 1950-1952 (Folder 4)
            - General
            - Senate Internal Security Subcommittee hearing transcripts
      - AWARE, Inc. (Folder 5)
        - General. Clippings, memoranda, pamphlets, press releases, reports, 1952-1956